Gareth Patterson

Charlotte, NC | patteg7@gmail.com | 973 908-9082

SUMMARY

Being fully self-taught, I have organically cultivated a deep interest in the software space. Coming from a people-oriented background, I find strength in my communication skills. Having served in client facing roles, I am strong in translating business needs into technology deliverables. Likewise, I breakdown complex topics into digestible pieces for stakeholders across all business functions. A track record of exceeding growth expectations in terms of technology and communication.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- MongoDB/NoSQL
- Data Structures

- JavaScript/Node.js
- SQL/SQLite
- Cloud Computing

- Linux/Bash
- Django/Flask
- Networking

Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900, AWS Certified Developer: Associate Expected August 2023

EXPERIENCE

Endava – IT Service and Consulting

Capital Market BDR

Charlotte, NC

Jan 2023 - Current

- Served as Full-Stack Python Developer on internal project.
- Communicate with clients on database capabilities, NoSQL, MySQL
- Software and Business value of Data Management, Trading Platforms build-out, Cloud Migration
- Conducted requirement gathering; Sales, Delivery, Legal, and Development teams

Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity

Charlotte, NC

Growth Consultant

IT Technician

Jun 2022-Dec 2022

- Calendar and SharePoint Organization for student meetings
- Built Excel Budget to track \$400,000 per year using functions and Power Queries

IT - Independent Contractor

Raritan Center, NJ

Sep 2019-Jun 2022

- Hardware Networking of network cables across 150,000 sq ft. complex
- Usage of Linux to remotely access machines and troubleshoot
- Monitored incoming data and Web Files for prohibited content

LEADERSHIP

Iota Tau Housing Corporation

Sep 2022–Current

• Developed alumni retention plan that increased turnout to events by 130%

Drug Overdose Prevention Program – Rutgers University

Nov 2021-May 2022

• Founder of Program serving 3500 Members of Rutgers Greek Life

Ability Experience

• Volunteered for Crew Chief for the Journey of Hope cross-country cycling event.

PROJECTS

LLM/AI Supply chain Workflow - Endava

Jul 2023-Current

Technologies: Django, Python, Vue, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- Utilizing Django to create a user-friendly frontend and complex backend
- In charge of creating API for LLM

Movie Review Site Jun 2023

Technologies: MongoDB, Python

- Created an API to have a fully managed NoSQL database used through a CLI.
- Connected multiple locally hosted Databases

EDUCATION

Rutgers University B.A. in History and Political Science New Brunswick, NJ

Graduated May 2022